Can hear me well.
Hello everyone. Welcome. This is the tutorial session
for
3D scanners, I'm here the textile lab and we're
going to show the two technologies we have available
here. One of them is the connect.
And the connect is actually the device from Xbox to
map out a room. So on those buddy
games that you can do things
with your arms. It's the one used but you can
also use it for today's scanning and you can
just play okay?
I have multiple cameras going on overwhelming, but
I'll try.
Probably you can see on the other camera there where it's at
Excel at Amsterdam. The mannequin I have
and the setup that I have to connect here in front of it and
we have an amazing.
Do it in the lab rotation table.
So basically with a little
cord there and the bottom is a rotating chair.
We can rotate our body steadily enough
to for the laser cut to
work.
so let's
see next
Can someone say something just for me to know if my speakers are
working because I had to mute I yes, thank
you.
So I'm gonna share my screen.
Moment.
For you to see the interface of the connect.
So here I'm using skill net software. This
is a free version. I think it has some limitations but
it's one that you can download and then you can use the connect
itself without the Xbox. So then you don't
need to have the Xbox to use it.
I'm using it on a Mac. I try to set up on the windows that
we have here, but then for Windows is not so Plug and Play
you need to download the drives as well for the kinet. And then later to
function I couldn't have it working. But I also have older windows. So
I'm not sure what was the problem there on the Mac was
quite straightforward. Just plugging in the connect with
the USB downloaded in scan it and was already
recognizing.
So the first thing you want to do here on the
software is just to press new and then you
have some resetting so body object room have
room usually the connect as it's
meant for tracking room. It works better
in bigger and
Spaces or bigger objects if you're trying to do something very detailed.
It doesn't work that well, but here we want to
then scan body. So we have our mannequin over
there. So then it creates a bounding box. This is something that it
changes as you change this preset settings, but
you can also override it and just select a bit more. So for
instance, I'm going to do here two by two
by two.
work in different aspects radios and you can
where this is going to be saved, but I leave everything as
default and I just
press start then I go to the second part of the menu here on top.
And here you can if you're connected is working properly.
You can already see a body figure
there on the top. Otherwise, if
you don't say anything then there is some problem you need to
to solve that before starting. Let me just
see if ours. Yeah, you can delay the
Start by certain seconds here. If you need
still to do something to adjust or you can just leave to
nothing and you can add a limit. This is until when it's
going to keep recording and then you're going to record your shape.
Since we have it a steady body that is not
a person it won't move. But if you're doing this with someone
then this is the moment that you really hold still and
then you press start and you try to have a neutral
face or a laughing face. If you can hold that one for long and in
our case since we have a rotating table, I'm going to start rotating
it very slowly. Another way to
do it is to have someone sitting on a chair and very slowly
also rotating this chair.
Another way is to rotate the device
on the person but for The Connect usually we don't do that.
We do that more with the sense, which is the second one. I'm going to show.
So then let's start I'm going to put just three
seconds delay. I press here record.
It's going to count the tree and the
green part is where it's recognizing. So it's
also not recognizing the
the back wall as my object. I hope that as
I move it's gonna let go back
well.
You do need to go right now.
It depends a bit on the Shadows of
the of the rumors where I'm starting again because
we're standing too much of the of the wall back there.
So
indeed
Okay now, let's see.
Yeah still notifications.
Later on the edit process. You can also remove
eventual
objects that are unwanted
I feel like fishing.
Well, it's losing.
What's
And Jacob
is read.
Signing in let me go back all the way to the front.
But now this is a very bad skin showed your
whole form is not as you want.
So just for you to see if I move forward what was coming
out of this skin.
But you see that it's not.
the idea
so we have a very blurred object with a
wall behind.
It's always a good idea also to play a bit with the
lights. So here we have some lines from the top Lady. It's their
Community or let's see if the natural
light if it works a bit better.
to
you
then you
Yes, okay. Let's see.
say
yeah, I'm
gonna start again.
So, this is a fun part of life tutorials because I just
did it before we started and then now of course
it's not working. But let's see if it works. It's grabbing a
little bit of the head, but I think it's more Central now
and getting less walls. Let's hope
Yeah, a lot of positive.
you
yeah, it's lost it already.
Like it's not really.
so again,
just wait to see what came out of it, but
Because we did not a good skin.
Let's try again.
We are trying some different settings not to get the wall
into it. If someone has also a tip because I
put here.
Against the white wall because also that helps the
contrast and before it was recognizing it
quite well, but I'll keep trying again and then
I just move forward with whatever we get and later
on issue on the second option so that we
don't get stuck into failing.
But that's also been how it goes with 3D scanning. Like I usually
have to take quite a while setting up.
he
Okay, I change the bounding box to
one to one so then it is not getting the background
now. So let's see if this helps a bit
object.
It was already selected as body but I had
a bounding box a bit bigger because this is bigger than one to one but then
by doing so it was also getting the wall
behind it. Not sure why but then now appears to
be getting the body better.
Then you need to go very very slow.
It's getting some trouble on the back. There's quite some Shadow. There's
no.
I'm safe. Stop you.
Advanced Techniques
no, just got some more and
oh, yeah, and
it's almost
back to our started.
And I get back there.
I can just post.
So this must be a decent one. So
I just pause recording here. It's gonna process down
there.
Then you oh, no, you need to go to reconstruct. Sorry.
Finalizing match then
it really depends on how big it's
watching. How also Define this
you can take longer.
Yeah, here it is. We have some more
but we can clean that but our body is quite distant
and this I hope on the
Closing the mesh we get sort of okay back, but
we could do it again later on trying to
have some less shadow.
If you're using if you want to use a
very detailed module, you can at this
step click on Fusion, but for us it's not needed
and also takes a while to process it. So you can try later on when
you're scanning and then here in process, it's some of
the of the process that you can do with this 3D
model. So one of them is watertight. So
you're just basically gonna close it as one
close surface.
so now it's filling in the holes and
And I hope this wall is going to go away just by
doing it. Otherwise, you also need to clean.
the wall
Yeah, so now it's done
it also colored. My back
is a bit weird, but it's sort of
the front is quite
okay and depending on what you're doing. This could be good enough or you
could run another time.
Then you can do some other edits you
can send it to edit external edit,
but you can also hear simplify the mesh
reducing the number of faces you could
fill in holes holes. Sorry,
you can crop and then this is
one.
Crop to ground. Let's see if oh, I
should have.
moved first
it's a bit.
Yeah, so here by putting
it up and down you're sinking your object into
the ground. So if you want to have a very
straight base and in my case in some using that.
This this wood. I don't want it to have it on my
object so I can crop it over there.
It is a bit annoying to see because the command
is on top of
your future
and you can also tilt
it a bit.
Yeah, so I'm happy with this.
rubbed ground
Yeah.
And they can also remove Parts
smaller in the percentage of the biggest model part this one.
I'm not sure.
That's yes, it worked.
You can either live the colors on or you
can remove the colors so you can just keep your
Treat object without colors and this
would be good already to be exported. So you
can export it like this and on the
export process you can support it
and save it as an OBG or as a St L
as
just
So here sport object, you have the different.
extensions you can support and also the different
scale and
color and
if you
And it's exporting. I will
stop sharing so I can change to the sense.
But I have
the sense in a Windows computer that I don't I'm not connected to
the internet so I won't be able to share screen.
So it's just explaining and demoing Via
this other computer.
The sense is a tool like this one.
It's basically plug in play. So you have a USB
connection. You put it on your computer and
then you need the sense software to
run it. But this one you can either do
it coding it steady and object running.
Moving in the platform like we did or you
can also use this one to walk around. It doesn't
have such a long cable. So it doesn't allow you to go. So yeah
so wild with it,
but it works well with not so steady
and then you go recognizing the object As you move so I'm
going to connect this one.
Okay, we have some very Advanced screen
Sherry here.
first two computers, but this is the
sense software. Oops. I need
the other Mouse.
It is quite simple and intuitive
setting I'm going to put head and I'm
going to try just to do the head of my object which is over
here. You could also do body because it would
recognize bit more. I'll leave it boy on and then
you basically start scanning so you don't have a lot of settings to
restart later on you can do the same as we just saw close
the object and do some extra
manipulation. So I'll start skinny,
and I don't know if you see with my other hand, but
I'm pointing it to there so probably
Okay.
Then the challenge here is to keep following a
screen while you have to either
move around. But in this case, I'm going to try to
keep it the base and Marika. My
assistant is gonna turn the platform.
Yeah, you can start.
Go slow and then it tells you to hold still when
it still capturing. So it's not saying
please go still then you can keep moving.
What?
Do you stop?
Sometimes it's a little distract and then you need to go back
a little bit where he lost but it's still good.
You keep going.
Yeah.
and
oh, it's the court finished.
This this one gives more flexibility to point from
the top and the bottom and so you really get the
whole badge for instance get hair details.
Stop a bit.
We'll use this on.
Okay.
You can continue. Let's see if it gets back
to it.
Yeah.
Yeah, you can go.
All right,
I would say it's always started somewhere
here so you can then go and
Oh false.
Let's now I can with this
one. You can also pause and restart. Okay, sorry.
But as you say that this is good and we could
finish to see how it finished up the model.
Maybe you can show yearly net how I was
doing it with the things. So I had this
one in my head and then I was just this holding it steady
and we were rotating this one, but you can
also do the other way around that you rotate if you're rotating
making sure that that's that Circle that was showing
in the middle. It's always pointing to the same height of
your object. So this is really something that
And yes that this is something that really makes it keep in
place. If you lose track try to go
back to where you started or some some of the spot that
you've been already true so that it finds again and that's
basically it.
It's still processing.
and
yes.
So when it takes long either is too good or
too bad.
that
okay, so we have it like the other one also some wall
over here, but
it looks sort of okay. I was not really aimed pointing
to the hands. So it's we
would crop it from the rest up
and then this one yeah you can
do.
so
now the trim but this is a sort of a to-do dream.
Then you can also solidify your model.
And you would get a closed smash something that
it's a good enough here. Do the
same. You can also crop the bottom doing it and then you
have also color or no color increase a
bit brightness contrast and do
some basic settings.
And then if you're happy with it.
oops
finish
and then you know export and then
here you have also the option so OBG STL
files and then you export or you just
saved this model to export later on.
So that's basically it. Thank you.
Is there any doubts I think
it's more also a bit of a using this devices to
understand how they work as well.
I'll just you can
turn this camera.
I don't know if Claudia or Anastasia right there. Oh you're
there.
Larger are you talking I'm not listening.
It's not working.
Yes, yes.
as work
Okay.
You hear me?
Yep. Yep. Okay. Thank you. So here we
have the older version of the sense.
And I'm just sharing from
that works. So you can only see the interface is
slightly similar to the one that better it was
using.
and we
we have the same features basically and we're gonna try
to make a scan of this managing
that was previously less a cuts
and assembled like the assignment of the week is required.
And we're gonna try to see what happens.
It was kind of.
So as you can see from the screen, you have
the option to decide if you're gonna scan a
small object a medium object or a large object. We're gonna
go for the medium.
and in the same way
before you sew through the color you can recognize if
you are too close.
Or too far from the object. It's a
good practice to keep 45 degrees. For example.
From the laser towards a point you're trying
to scan.
And also if you have a turning table,
so for example, we're using a store. It's something
very useful if you want to keep yourself
in the same position.
So we trying to do something really
quick without moving.
And we can start.
So press the start.
Of course. Also, there are settings like hidden buttons
that you can adjust.
for example the resolution
so you're not gonna end up with a really heavy mesh.
Okay, we are officially starting and I'm
trying to slowly rotate.
the table
Okay.
That's sick. We already lost tracking.
always going to fast Maybe
I start over.
start
also try to move up and down.
To catch this model is a bit complex
and challenging but we have done it before so we're
sure that the result might come and a
nice way.
If you're trying to scan for example spaces Instead try
to go.
up
So sometimes tricky point is to
cover and to close the holes. That
might come when you come the head from Top.
We're just demonstrating a small
object. So so far everything. You looks
good.
Of course the more time you spend scanning the
object the more precise your mesh would be at the end, but
I think more or less we're good to go.
Okay, so, let's see what we got.
We can go next.
Just simple buttons and our scan
will get with us.
Okay, it's full of holes, but it's
something that's also wait so previously into account and
we can just try to see
with the
basic options like solidify. For example, what kind of effect.
With that in order to close the machine to
a solid.
So this way we will get an STL and an
obj if we want to keep the texture and the
color of the materials.
Should be ready.
Okay.
This is not about right.
And of course you can also if you spot any
more words, but this should be should be
a pretty much a watertight solid so you
can actually start exporting this
mesh and play around with another software for
example mesh mixer.
Rhino fusion and so on so
you can just do next.
and Save
as still for example of obj in
case as we said if you want to keep the colors and the textures.
now we have another Spanish
we want to
to show
you can stop screenshot in here.
and we can get
connected
I'm just
going to show just
okay. So where trying to use
the Arctic?
It's a professional strategy discount
there.
That uses the same technology as the sense this
structured like so it's going to project them up
of light.
This should be connected so.
The scanner this and we want you to show.
A really stunning we did this morning.
Now you can
see the screen.
So if you want to compare this can
with the one we saw before.
This one is more professional.
This course you can spot from the 3D model itself.
So here we managed to got all
these details.
I know.
You can see three from the physical objects.
and even the label
of the soap
This is a professional scanner for for example
Healthcare applications Orthopedics City
assistive Technologies.
Usually you're not find this in the lab, but for the things
that you are scanning something like sense is
very good to separate. It works
in a similar way, but as you can see the interface of the
software here you have many more settings to play with.
So for example, if you want to
try a demo and actually went to
show you
um the workflow of this
so for example here
This is the result that you are showing seeing here
of different kind of Skies that we can do separately. So
everything is not recorded and
scanned all at once but in different steps
so you can decide for example to scan the top
part.
Itself or the front or the side?
and here you see
the amount for example of surfaces that
were called that
something like 500 recession
so you can resume.
And you can pause every time you need to get
the best site of your 3D object.
And at the end you can run the
autopilot you can tell and you can ask this software.
Too much all this coming together into an
object. And of course there are other tools to fix
holes to add it to clean.
These are very complex mesh. For example, let me
take a while to scan. So also in terms of for example
of the sides. It will be much heavier than
one so before
I think we can just try to
stop screen share.
and do something like
and so then
You know.
just
So, okay.
So we can make a new one.
What's something always good
to keep in mind is to try
to scan objects not reflective
or transparent like for example bottles.
In case this space is a bit challenging because it's really
shiny white. So it's actually a bit
reflective.
But for this scanner was was a good
demonstration.
Yeah, we can try to scan the same mannequin.
And the process is the same.
Yeah, we can start just to demonstrate a
bit.
when
It's of course and it scans an object. Of course
the resolution here for example is something like 0.05 millimeters.
So sometimes is also very tricky
to be stable and to keep the same position.
There are also features like the temperature.
scanner
and you can say that the photographs per second.
The speed of it is much faster compared to
the previous kindness.
Okay. So for example, we can catch one side and we can
stop it.
Also, this match is really hard.
What we can just show for example and start.
Another scanning we did last week that was
this Makita Andre.
And this is the result of the 3D model in the
3D viewer of the computer. So this is the object.
The physical and at the same time you can see that the
same amount of textures buttons.
and little details
There's been also recorded.
here in the physical and the Digital model
How long did it take?
20 minutes
yeah, and also of course, this is the STL but
If you have the obj you
will spot all the logos or the labels all the
buttons and the colors of different.
Okay, I guess that's all.
I don't know if you have questions.
or
Curiosities we can
Yeah, we just ended.
I don't know if in anybody else questions or
Curiosities we can answer.
Sometimes it's very tricky to use to computers and to
show at the same time to the people in the lab with the
students everything. That's that's happening.
Okay, I think.
We're good for today.
Yes, awesome.
So if if you don't have
a scanner and make sure
that you can download different applications on
the phone and also highly
encourage you to try photography with
the pictures with the photos. That's really working.
It is all very very robust.
Let's say technology so
you can also try that.
Yeah, and you find a lot of already and our
website and a classic five different resources in terms
of some website that you can check and try out.
Okay. Thank you everyone.